<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life in a Shell</title>
    <link>http://rFronteddu.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Life in a Shell</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 20:19:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://rFronteddu.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Assigning a capacity to data structures is important</title>
      <link>http://rFronteddu.github.io/posts/alwaysaddsize/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 20:19:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rFronteddu.github.io/posts/alwaysaddsize/</guid>
      <description>For years I underestimated the importance of fixing the capacity of my data structures. Today while I was tracking a nasty bug in one of my software I finally realized that has to stop. After some thinking these are the conclusions I arrived: By assigning a size…
 It is possible to understand more easily what “pipe” has filled in situations where the memory allocation keeps slowly escalating (either because it is not released or because new data is generated more frequently than consumed) and consequently not being overwhelmed during the fixing process; It is possible to keep track of performances by being warned about structures that are frequently filled; It is possibly to keep under control the memory footprint of the software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Globbing</title>
      <link>http://rFronteddu.github.io/posts/globbing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 23:24:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rFronteddu.github.io/posts/globbing/</guid>
      <description>Today I was playing with hugo and I wanted to automate my pipeline a bit so I made a script that looked like this:
eval &#39;rm -rv !(&amp;quot;hugo&amp;quot;|*.sh)&#39;  But I quickly discovered that even if that would work on a shell it would not work on a script. That is because a script doesn&amp;rsquo;t know how to process globbing (round parentesys expansion). To fix that I enabled glob changing the script as follows:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://rFronteddu.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rFronteddu.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi! My name is Roberto Fronteddu and I am from Longastrino, Italy. Longastrino is a little town in the middle of nowhere. I grew up biking around swamps, serving coffees at my parents’ bar, eating pizza during the weekend (my father used to be a pizza maker), and playing lots of video games. I figured out I wanted to be a software developer pretty quickly (either that or hobo martial artist) but it took a while before I could get into that.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
