<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Life in a Shell</title>
    <link>http://rFronteddu.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Life in a Shell</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 12:10:28 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://rFronteddu.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On Ego, Mistakes, and the Soul of Mastery</title>
      <link>http://rFronteddu.github.io/posts/maestro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 12:10:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rFronteddu.github.io/posts/maestro/</guid>
      <description>In the tapestry of these past moons, I, a wanderer of codes, have traversed realms, crafting visions in diverse programming tongues. From the ethereal realms of low-level C++, where custom network protocols dance, to the sacred shores of a nascent data lake, where a NiFi pipeline unfurls its serpentine beauty. Alas, amidst this symphony of creation, I stumbled upon a disheartening truth—a recurring melody in my recent mistakes, born of shallow introspection and hasty assumptions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gradle, Spring, and React, Part 1</title>
      <link>http://rFronteddu.github.io/posts/gradlespringreact1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 21:55:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rFronteddu.github.io/posts/gradlespringreact1/</guid>
      <description>In the past few days I decided to spend some time playing with the spring framework.
My favorite build environment for JAVA is gradle, so the first step was to figure out how to have Webpack and NPN seamlessly work together.
I also like for my code to support being compiled from both Windows and Linux. The major issue was how to configure the gradle build file. In fact, by following the instruction found online, WebPack and NPN would fail on Windows for multiple reasons (one of them was path related).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assigning a capacity to data structures is important</title>
      <link>http://rFronteddu.github.io/posts/alwaysaddsize/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 20:19:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rFronteddu.github.io/posts/alwaysaddsize/</guid>
      <description>For years I underestimated the importance of fixing the capacity of my data structures. Today while I was tracking a nasty bug in one of my software I finally realized that has to stop. After some thinking these are the conclusions I arrived: By assigning a size…
 It is possible to understand more easily what “pipe” has filled in situations where the memory allocation keeps slowly escalating (either because it is not released or because new data is generated more frequently than consumed) and consequently not being overwhelmed during the fixing process; It is possible to keep track of performances by being warned about structures that are frequently filled; It is possibly to keep under control the memory footprint of the software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Globbing</title>
      <link>http://rFronteddu.github.io/posts/globbing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 23:24:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rFronteddu.github.io/posts/globbing/</guid>
      <description>Today I was playing with hugo and I wanted to automate my pipeline a bit so I made a script that looked like this:
eval &#39;rm -rv !(&amp;quot;hugo&amp;quot;|*.sh)&#39;  But I quickly discovered that even if that would work on a shell it would not work on a script. That is because a script doesn&amp;rsquo;t know how to process globbing (round parentesys expansion). To fix that I enabled glob changing the script as follows:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>